All eyes are on Google this week as they
are preparing for a highly anticipated
launch of the Gemini 3.0 as we have
showcased on this channel. But
unexpectedly today, Google dropped
another new advancement with the release
of Gemini 2.5 computer use. This is now
available in preview via API as well as
the Google AI studio. But this new
computer use model is a specialized
extension of the Gemini 2.5 Pro. It's
designed to power AI agents that can
interact directly with user interfaces.
And I've got to say, it's pretty
impressive. In terms of its performance,
it currently ranks number one,
outperforming leading alternatives like
Anthropics Sonnet 4.5, as well as Open
AI's computer agent on multiple
benchmarks. Google says the model
delivers industry-leading browser
control with its low latency based on
its performance on the browserbased
harness. Just take a look at this
example where the Gemini 2.5 computer
use is able to open up a pet setup store
and it is finding different dog breeds
within California. It pulls up their
details and then it switches to the
spa's CRM site where it fills out all
the information, adds the pet as a
guest, and it books a follow-up
appointment with the different
customer's name. And this is for a
particular date which is October 10th
after 8:00 a.m. using the same treatment
they originally requested. So you can
see that it is able to follow user
instructions pretty precise and it's a
lot faster than what we saw previously
with the previous version of the
computer use. Here is another demo where
Gemini 2.5 goes to a sticky note jam
website, reads the messy digital board
and identifies all the art club tasks.
It understands the user predefined
categories and then it drags each sticky
note into the right section which is
actually pretty impressive. Gemini 2.5
computer use operates in a continuous
agent loop which you can see over here.
It takes in the user request. It
screenshots the current interface like
how it did before and then a short
history of previous actions will also be
used for future generations. So using
this context, the model then decides the
next UI action, whether that's clicking
a button, typing a text, or dragging the
element. And then it can even ask for
user confirmation when it's needed. But
once the action is actually executed,
the environment sends back an updated
screenshot as well as a URL. So it
allows the model to analyze the new
state and it continues the loop until
the task is complete. This cycle enables
Gemini to interact with the real web
interfaces autonomously. efficiently and
safely. Before we get started, I just
want to mention that you should
definitely go ahead and subscribe to the
World of AI newsletter. I'm constantly
posting different newsletters on a
weekly basis. So, this is where you can
easily get up-to-date knowledge about
what is happening in the AI space. So,
definitely go ahead and subscribe as
this is completely for free. Now, to
access this new Gemini 2.5 computer use,
you can definitely do so through the
hosted version off of browser base. This
is where you can access it and test it
out over here. It's called Gemini
browser and you can send in any natural
language prompt and you can watch how
the AI browses the web. So you can tell
it to get the latest crypto prices. Send
in this prompt and it will execute it
using this new computer used model.
Another way to access it is through the
Google AI studio by accessing the API
and then you can use it locally to run
different sorts of tasks. Now, I'm just
testing it out over here on the Gemini
browser base before I use it with
something like Kilo Code. And this is
where I'm going to have it first review
a pull request. This is one prompt that
I'm testing to see how fast it is in
terms of taking in multiple
instructions. This is where we're having
it uh go over to the GitHub repository
for browser base, which is called stage
hands, and we're making sure the
combination evolves and the PR
validation are passed. Now, this is
where we're trying to see how fast it is
in terms of navigating through all the
different component libraries within the
repo and seeing how fast it is in terms
of providing us the result that we are
requiring. It's been 1 minute and 18
seconds and so far it is now navigating
to the pull request section of stage
hands. Finally, we are at the last step
where it has evaluated that was opened.
Now it is checking the combination
evolves in the PR validation and seeing
if they're passed or not. Unfortunately,
I missed the screen recording for the
section where it was able to evaluate
the success, but it took approximately 3
minutes and it was able to finish the
task and give us the summary of what it
had accomplished. Now, in terms of its
input token limit, it has 128K limit and
for its output, it's listed at 64K.
Now, guys, if you're looking to set this
up locally and implement the computer
use, you're going to need to make sure
you have a couple of dependencies
installed beforehand, you're going to
need to make sure you have Playright
installed. You can use the pip install
command within your terminal to install
it. Then, all you got to do is just get
an API key from the Google AI Studio.
You're going to need to make sure it's
connected to a billing account. Then you
can create a computer use folder and
then within that folder create a Python
file. Name it whatever you want. You can
name it computer use. And then when you
have opened up VS code or whatever ID
you have you can open up that computer
use Python file. And now you can set up
all the different computer use scripts
like sending a request to the model. You
can define it by receiving the model
response executing the received actions.
There's a couple things that you can set
like building the agent loop. So use
this docs to help you build the script
that you can use to implement the
computer use for your local use cases.
So there we go. I have set my Python
script and this is where it's going to
be using the Gemini 2.5 computer use
agent for gathering the top five
trending AI research papers. And let's
see how fast it is in comparison to the
results we got from the Gemini browser
base. And there we go. I just ran the
script and you can see right now it is
now using the computer use to go over to
archive and find the top five trending
AI research papers. So, so far what I've
realized is that if you are to run
scripts using this new Gemini 2.5
computer use model, it is a lot faster
and more efficient than the Gemini
browser. So, if you're looking to get
started with it locally, I believe that
is the best option. Use the its
capabilities to get the best out of it.
Let's run another example where we're
going to have it fetch the latest price
of Bitcoin as well as Ethereum. And
let's see if it's able to do this a lot
faster than what we saw with the
previous example.
So, one thing I noticed is that it got
the correct price for Bitcoin, but it
also searched the price of Ethereum on
Google and it didn't seem to find the
correct answer it was looking for. So
now it's looking for prices off of
Coinbase to provide me the correct
answer for the price of Ethereum. If you
like this video and would love to
support the channel, you can consider
donating to my channel through the super
thanks option below. Or you can consider
joining our private Discord where you
can access multiple subscriptions to
different AI tools for free on a monthly
basis, plus daily AI news and exclusive
content, plus a lot more. But that's
about it guys for today's video on the
new Gemini 2.5 computer use model. It's
a pretty impressive model that's
definitely more efficient and a lot more
precise in comparison to the computer
use we saw from Enthropic and it's a lot
better than what we saw initially from
Gemini with its computer use agent. But
let's see how impressive it gets with
the Gemini 3.0 model when it's
officially released maybe in the next
couple of weeks or even this week. But
that's basically it guys. I hope you
enjoyed today's video and got some sort
of value. I'll leave all these links in
the description below so that you can
easily get started. Make sure you go
ahead and subscribe to the second
channel. Make sure you go ahead and join
the newsletter, join our private
Discord, follow me on Twitter, and
lastly, make sure you guys subscribe,
turn on notification bell, like this
video, and please take a look at our
previous videos because there's a lot of
content that you'll truly benefit from.
But with that thought, guys, have an
amazing day, spread positivity, and I'll
see you guys fairly shortly. He suffers.